天啊
Oh, man.
终于到了这一刻
This is really happening.
你还好吗
You doin' okay?
又来一波阵痛了
Here comes another contraction.
加速啊
Let's pick it up!
好  坐稳了
All right, hold on.
我要用我们印度当地的方式开车了
I'm gonna drive like we do in India.
死一边去  你个梅毒贱狗
Get out of my way, you syphilitic dogs!
别这样  这里不是印度
Stop that! This isn't India.
好吧
Fine.
堂堂13亿人口大国的人哪懂生孩子的事啊
What do one point three billion people know about having babies?
对不起啦  我知道你也是想帮忙
Sorry. I know you were just trying to help.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你啦  没事的
I love you, too. We're good.
艾米
Amy?
醒醒
Wake up.
怎么了
Wh... What's wrong?
现在是午夜
It's midnight.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
谢尔顿
Sheldon.
这个东西先没收  早上起床后还你
Okay, you can have this back in the morning.
这是给你的
This is for you.
我本来打算把它包好
I was going to wrap it,
但是想到要碰透明胶布我就浑身发毛
but touching Scotch tape gives me the heebie-jeebies.
我会记得你不喜欢胶布  桃子与毡制品
I'll put in on the list with peaches and felt.
这是什么
What is this?
我大脑的功能性磁共振成像
A functional MRI of my brain.
我在拍之前做了一把数独来显得更脑力惊人
I did Sudoku before they took it so I'd be ripped.
我喜欢  谢谢你
I love it. Thank you.
而且玄机不止如此
And it's not just an MRI.
我的大脑眼窝前额皮质是亮起的
The orbitofrontal cortex is lit up
因为我当时想着你
because I was thinking of you.
谢尔顿
Sheldon!
我们貌似又来到了你生日庆典中的
We seem to be moving on to the annual coitus portion
年度交媾仪式了
of your birthday festivities.
可以吗
Is that okay?
不然我穿诱人格子睡衣是为啥呢
I didn't put on my come-hither plaid PJ's for nothing.
你讨厌透明[苏格兰]胶带  却喜欢苏格兰格纹
You hate Scotch tape, but you love Scotch plaid.
迷一般的男人啊
You are a mystery.
你们快起床
Guys, wake up!
伯纳黛特要生啦
Bernadette's having her baby!
起床  我们要去医院了
Come on, we're going to the hospital!
我想...  我想我们得先停下
I guess... I guess we should stop.
恐怕是的
Yeah. I'm afraid so.
生孩子  差点交媾
Childbirth, looming coitus?
这可真是个女性生殖器官的精彩之夜
This is a banner night for female genitals.
旁边有三个男的
Now I see three of you.
知道谁是生父吗  还是像《妈妈咪呀》那样
Do we know the father, or is this some Mamma Mia nonsense?
这部音乐剧中  女主角结婚想请父亲来
但是妈妈的三个旧情人中  并不知道谁才是生父
我是孩子的爹
I'm the father.
孩子的爹  阵痛间隔是多久
Okay, Dad, how far apart are the contractions?
不知道  问他
No idea. Ask him.
12分钟
12 minutes.
12分钟吗  那你们来干嘛
12 minutes? Why are you here?
不是应该提早一个半小时到场吗
Aren't we supposed to get here an hour and a half early?
这里是医院  不是机场
This is a hospital, not the airport.
对不起了  我们第一次生孩子
I'm sorry. It's our first time.
没事的
It's okay.
小家伙很快就会出生了
This little one will be here before you know it.
知道会是男孩还是女孩吗
Do we know what we're having?
不知道  我们想留个惊喜
No, we're keeping it a surprise.
传统作风  我喜欢
Old school. Nice.
也没那么传统  他知道
Not that old school. He knows.
是这样嘛  我当时在医生办公室嘛
You see, I was at the doctor's office,
然后孩子档案就放在那边嘛  我就偷看一眼嘛
the folder was right there, so I took a peek.
就算你这么说  那件事也还是很变态嘛
And talking like this doesn't make it less creepy.
亲爱的  你先回家
Sweetheart, go home.
等阵痛间隔5分钟持续一小时后再来
Come back when the contractions are five minutes apart for an hour.
抱歉  这说得有点不清楚
I'm sorry. That's ambiguous.
这间隔五分钟是包含第一次的这一个小时
Is it five minutes apart starting at the top of the hour,
还是第一次5分钟间隔阵痛后一小时
or five minutes apart starting with the first contraction,
所以基本上就是维持65分钟后
so essentially, like, 65 minutes?
我就随口这么一说
I'm just throwing this out there,
但这年头家中分娩也挺流行的
but home births are very popular these days.
谢尔顿  为什么你拖这么久
Sheldon, what took you so long?
生孩子父亲都会发雪茄庆祝
Wolowitz might hand out cigars.
所以我得找出我的泡泡糖雪茄
I had to find my bubble gum cigar
到时才能不像个傻逼地加入大家
so I could join in without looking foolish.
靠  我得去拿我气喘药
Damn, I need my inhaler.
你别跟着抽就好啦
Just don't smoke.
不是  是我下楼跑太快
No, I went down the stairs too fast.
别来医院  我们要回家了
Don't come to the hospital. We're headed home.
这也太快了  她是打喷嚏把孩子打出来了吗
Oh, that was fast. Did she sneeze the baby out?
我们太早就去医院了  有新情况再通知你
We showed up too early. We'll keep you posted.
好吧  那我们之后再联系  再见
Okay, well, we'll talk to you guys later. Bye.
她说先别去  还得一阵子
She said not to come. It's gonna be a while.
第一胎是有可能拖很久
Well, first deliveries can be slow.
我开始犹豫买给这孩子的闪电侠哈衣对不对了
I am starting to rethink the Flash onesie I bought this kid.
我找到了  但是里面空了
I found it, but it's empty.
无所谓了  我们现在先不去医院了
Well, it doesn't matter. We're not going to the hospital now.
你确定吗  我还挺想去的
Are you sure? I'd really like to.
那我们是不是要...  再回去啊
Well, should we, uh, head back up?
大家来嘛
Come on, guys.
反正都起来了  一起去个小餐厅之类的啊
We're all awake. Why don't we go to a diner or something?
不知道啊
Oh, uh, I don't know.
谢尔顿  你不想去的  对吧
Sheldon, you don't want to do that, do you?
我想不想去不是重点啊
It doesn't matter what I want.
-今天是你生日  寿星最大  -天啊
- It's your birthday. You decide. - Oh, my God!
是你生日啊  一起去做点好玩的
It's your birthday! Let's do something fun.
我们可以一起去酒吧
Well, we could go to a bar.
这个嘛...
Well...
好了  我又能呼吸了  亲爱的  他们想做爱
Okay, I can breathe again. Babe, they want to have sex.
当然啊
Oh, of course!
年度生日庆祝打炮大典
The annual birthday booty spectacular!
你这样有点幼稚了吧
That's a bit childish, isn't it?
真不好意思啊  你的泡泡糖雪茄啥口味来着
I'm sorry, and what flavor is your bubble gum cigar?
葡萄  这口味最温和
Grape. I find it the most mild.
好吧  你们俩去好好快活
All right, well, you two go have fun.
如果我找到备用药  我们也能快活一把
If we find my backup inhaler, maybe we can get frisky.
你个性感气喘吁吁小家伙
Oh, you sexy, wheezy little man.
真的有需要录下来吗
Do you really need to record this?
以后你会感谢我的
You'll be happy I did.
好啦  小家伙  我们又回家来了
Okay, little one, here we are back at home
因为你还没完全准备好降生到这个世界上来
because you weren't quite ready to come out yet.
你隆重登场  我懂
You wanted to make an entrance. I get it.
你老爸在这呢
And here's your daddy.
当他想骗你说他过去很酷的时候
When he tries to tell you he used to be cool,
你可以眼见为实知道他并不酷
you can see he wasn't.
好了好了  别录了
All right, enough with the camera.
这又不是为我录的  是为宝宝录的
Well, this is not for me. This is for the baby.
有一天她会想看的
Some day she's gonna want to see this.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
你说谁会想看的
Who's gonna want to see this?
我说的是"她"
I-I said she,
但好多事物都是用"她"指代的
but lots of things are she --
比如船啊  车啊
boats and cars,
鲸鱼啊  比如  "瞧她喷水啦"
whales. Like, thar she blows.
圆场圆得好极了
You're doing great.
拉杰
Raj!
好吧  我先不录了
Well, okay, I'm gonna sign off now.
接下来这部分可能包含一些儿童不宜的语言
This next part may contain some adult language.
你怎么能这样
How could you?!
我们坚持到现在都不知道宝宝性别
We made it this far without knowing,
全被你毁了
and you ruined it!
你们根本不知道守着这么大个秘密
Well, you guys have no idea how hard it is
却谁也不能告诉有多难
to know something like this and not say it!
你早就告诉我是女儿了  我就没泄密
You told me it was a girl, and I didn't say it.
-拉杰  -你不该说出来的
- Raj! - You were supposed to keep that to yourself.
是啊  看来是挺难的
Oh, yeah. I guess it is hard.
那个  我们之前进行到哪了
So... where were we?
我很肯定
Well, I believe
我们之前正像欲求不满的青少年那样热吻
we were kissing like randy teenagers,
你的鼻子因为不通气轻轻地发出吹哨声
and your nose was whistling ever so slightly.
不好意思啊
I'm sorry.
没关系的
Oh, don't be.
你就像一只性感的茶壶
You were like a foxy tea kettle.
我们要重头来过吗
Well, shall we start over?
好的
Very well.
哪里不对头吗
What's wrong?
我也说不好
I'm not sure.
今晚早些时候  我们是自然而然开始的
Earlier tonight, things began organically,
现在感觉是为了做而做
and now it's feeling forced,
就像电影《加勒比海盗》那些续集一样
like all the Pirates of the Caribbean sequels.
好吧  这么说也有道理
Okay, that makes sense.
气氛的确是有点变了
I mean, the mood's a little different now.
我们不必急着做的
We-we don't have to rush.
我知道
Oh, I know,
但莱纳德和佩妮以为我们已经开搞了
but Leonard and Penny think we're doing it,
我不想让他们失望
and I don't want to disappoint them.
气氛继续急转直下
And the mood continues to change.
不是的  我当然也不想让你失望  我
No, and also, I don't want to disappoint you. I...
来吧  今天是你生日
You know, come on. It's your birthday.
我能咬牙挺过去
I can soldier through this.
等一下
H-Hold on.
我觉得我有份小惊喜
I think I might have a little surprise
或许能帮我们重回正轨
that might help get things back on track.
真撩人
Intriguing.
"重回正轨"是不是提示我
Is back on track a hint
小惊喜和火车有关
that it has something to do with trains?
不是
No.
因为如果和火车有关
Because if it did have to do with trains,
-而你又要  -和火车没关系
- and you were gonna give... - It's not about trains!
连东方快车的舒适软卧都...
Oh. Not even a cozy sleeper car on the Orient Express...
别再提火车了
Stop talking about trains!
还嫌别人破坏气氛呢
Who's killing the mood now?
我找到备用气喘药了  想爱爱吗
Found the backup inhaler. Want to have sex?
听到你这么说不想也想了
Well, I didn't until I heard that.
等一下  药还得憋几秒
Hang on. I'm counting.
好了
It's okay. Mm.
有人在家吗
Hello!
霍华德和伯纳黛特把我踢出来了
Howard and Bernadette kicked me out
因为我告诉他们宝宝是女儿
because I told them they're having a girl!
糟糕  又说漏嘴了
Oopsy, I did it again.
如果我们不出声  或许他会离开
Maybe if we're quiet, he'll go away.
可你这不就出声了吗
You're gonna have to be quieter than that.
我能睁开眼睛了吗
Can I look yet?
马上
One second.
好了  你可以睁开眼睛了
All right, you can open your eyes.
我想就让哈利·波特的魔法
I thought I'd let Harry Potter
让气氛变得"特"辣热起来吧
make things hotter.
要命了
Wowza.
我给你买了葛莱芬多的长袍
I got a Gryffindor robe for you.
葛莱芬多的人和赫奇帕奇的人搞在一起
A Gryffindor sleeping with a Hufflepuff?
竟有这等桃色丑闻
How scandalous.
你个淘气丫头
You naughty girl.
你居然不带我自己去了魔法世界
You went to the Wizarding World theme park without me.
没错
I did.
我惹上麻烦了吗
Am I in trouble?
你麻烦大了
Yes, you're in trouble --
你居然不带我自己去魔法世界
you went to Wizarding World without me!
等等  怎么风云突变
Wait, what just happened?
你明知道我一直想去的
You know I've been wanting to go.
谢尔顿  你真的想在我生日这天
Sheldon, do you really want to argue with me
和我吵架吗
on my birthday?
你说得对
Oh, you're right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
祝我生日快乐
Ooh. Happy birthday to me.
有人在家吗
Hello...
是宝宝有新情况了吗
Is this about the baby?
不  只是我走到哪都被人拒之门外
No. People just keep kicking me out everywhere I go.
很好  反正你都习惯了
Good. Then you're used to this.
伯纳黛特的羊水破了
Hey, Bernadette's water broke!
快走  都到医院去
Come on! Everyone to the hospital!
有没有搞错
You have got to be kidding me!
试着放松点  我们随时就到
Just try to relax. We'll be there any minute.
斯图尔特  别再像老头子一样开车了
Stuart, stop driving like an old man.
开快点
Speed it up a little.
我才不是老头子
I'm not an old man!
我只是一到晚上就看不清楚
I just can't see at night.
又开始宫缩了
Here comes another one.
老斜眼  右边那个才是油门
Hey, Squinty, the gas pedal's on the right!
好吧  坐稳了
All right, hang on.
如果你看到前面有路人  叫他们闪开
If you see any pedestrians, just call 'em out.
霍华德和伯纳黛特的宝宝
Howard and Bernadette's kid
可能在你的生日出生
might be born on your birthday.
这很酷吧
How cool is that?
是啊  但我以为这个宝宝本该毁掉的
Yeah, but I thought this baby was supposed to ruin
是他们的性生活  不是我的
their sex life, not mine.
这一天和我想象得一点都不一样
This is not how I imagined this day going --
此时此刻我应该陪在他们身边的
I should be with them right now.
可这是他们的宝宝啊
Well, it is their child.
我当然明白
I know that.
但平心而论  我花了九个月时间
But to be fair, I've spent nine months
帮助伯纳黛特做好迎接宝宝的准备
helping Bernadette get ready for this baby.
霍华德不过花了五分钟让她怀上宝宝而已
And Howard spent five minutes conceiving it.
说五分钟都是给他面子了
And I'm being generous.
才五分钟
Five minutes?
我们肯定哪里做错了
We must be doing it wrong.
我们一做好几个小时呢
It took us hours.
最糟糕的部分是
And-and the worst part is
他们居然把我赶走  让斯图尔特留下
that they kicked me out and let Stuart stay.
我理解你  但这特别的一天是属于他们的
I understand, but this is a special day for them.
你能不能别再计较了
Can you just try and let it go?
她说得对
She's right.
我刚刚得知艾米不带我自己去了主题公园
You know, I just learned Amy went to a theme park without me,
但我不会毁了她的生日
but I'm not going to ruin her birthday.
我会等  在接下来一年里
I'll wait, and ruin 24 individual hours
一次一小时  不定时毁足她24小时
sprinkled throughout the year.
深呼吸  慢慢地呼吸
Deep breaths, slow breaths.
我还是很渴  再给我点碎冰
I'm so thirsty. Give me more ice chips.
抱歉  我以为这是随屋赠送的碎冰
Sorry. I... thought these were room ice chips.
我去再拿些来
I'll go get some more.
斯图尔特  既然你出去了
Uh, Stuart, while you're out there,
就不用回来了
don't come back.
好
Okay.
我们给这孩子取什么名字呢
So, what are we gonna name this kid?
现在我们知道了是女孩
Now that we know she's a girl,
沃利·沃罗威茨这名字算是泡汤了
it kind of ruins my plan for Wally Wolowitz.
可以用你妈妈的名字
Could name her after your mom.
黛比
Debbie?
算了
No.
她讨厌这个名字
She hated that name.
她有中间名吗
Did she have a middle name?
玛尔维娜
Melvina.
我们继续想想
Let's keep thinking.
真讨厌  她不能在这陪着我们
It sucks that she's not here.
我懂
I know.
她还在的话  一定会是最棒的奶奶
She would've been the best grandma.
她的口袋里的确总是有糖果
She did always have candy in her pocket.
是啊
Yeah.
我到20岁时才明白
I was 20 years old before I figured out
巧克力卷并不是自带温度的
Tootsie Rolls weren't naturally warm.
我刚认识她五分钟  她就问我
I didn't know her five minutes and she asked,
你爱吃星河巧克力还是士力架
Are you a Milky Way or a Snickers girl?
谢天谢地你答对了  否则我们现在哪能在这里啊
Thank God you answered right, we wouldn't be here today.
真难相信霍华德要做父亲了
It's hard to believe Howard's having a kid.
就是
Yeah.
佩妮  是你把妮妮介绍给他的
Penny, you're the one who introduced him to Bernie.
我得说多少次对不起才行啊
How many times do I have to say I'm sorry?
不仅是霍华德和伯纳黛特
It's not just Howard and Bernadette. I mean,
看看我们的变化
look how far we've all come.
你俩结婚了
You two got married.
谢尔顿和我同居了
Sheldon and I are living together.
但如果我妈问起  就说我们睡的上下铺
But if my mom asks, we have bunk beds.
我们刚认识时  佩妮是个落魄的小演员
Penny was a struggling actress when we met,
现在她是成功的医药代表
and now she's a successful pharmaceutical rep.
你不用每次都强调落魄
Okay, you don't have to say struggling every time.
说演员就行
You can just say actress.
霍华德上过太空
Howard went to space.
伯纳黛特获得了博士学位
Bernadette got her doctorate.
谢尔顿  霍华德和我在为政府做
Sheldon, Howard and I are working with the government
量子陀螺仪
on our quantum gyroscope.
我们都有了长足的进步
We've all come a long way.
很多都值得骄傲
There's a lot to be proud of.
老天爷  你们干脆一刀捅死小爷算了
For God's sake, just drive in the knife, why don't you!
-你发什么疯  -你们都认为
- What's your problem? - Well, you're all thinking
我是唯一一个没有任何建树的人
that I'm the only one who hasn't done anything worthwhile.
我没这样想
I was not thinking it.
不过既然你自己挑明了  这的确是不可否认的事实
Although, now that you point it out, it is undeniable.
拉杰  希望这话能让你心理平衡一些
Raj, if it's any consolation,
我和十年前混得一样惨
I'm no better off than I was ten years ago.
好棒
Oh, yay!
我是天体物理学的博士
I have a doctorate in astrophysics
我和面色苍白的
and I'm every bit as awesome
漫画店老板一样"优秀"
as the pasty-faced owner of a comic book store!
拉杰  有点同情心好吗
Raj! Show some compassion.
这些话只能想  不能说出来
Those are things that we think but don't say.
失陪了
Excuse me.
抱歉  斯图尔特
Sorry, Stuart.
我在医院  但不是病人
Hey, I'm in a hospital and I'm not the patient.
我乐着呢
I'm fine.
好了  妮妮  呼吸
Come on, Bernie, breathe.
还记得在生产课上学的吗
Remember what you learned in birthing class.
我记得我觉得这样做很傻逼
I remember thinking, this is stupid,
我是对的
and I was right!
要我叫护士吗
Do you want me to get the nurse?
不要  再有人胆敢将手指靠近我的子宫
No! If one more person puts their fingers near my uterus,
我会用"夺命剪刀脚"将手指掰断
I'm gonna cross my legs and snap 'em off!
我与父母的关系得到了缓解
I've come to peace with my relationship with my parents.
对我来说这是重要的里程碑
That was a big milestone for me.
说到个人成长
Oh, speaking of personal growth,
我最近尝试吃了瑞士甜菜
I recently tried eating Swiss chard.
我只嚼没咽  但艾米说这样就很棒了
You know, I didn't swallow it, but Amy said it counted.
依然是废柴吗  还是说你离开的这段时间
Still a loser or did you turn things around
扭转乾坤  咸鱼翻身
while you were gone?
拉杰  亲爱的
You know, Raj, honey,
你对自己太严苛了
you're being too hard on yourself.
我刚认识你时  你甚至不敢跟女人说话
When I first met you, you couldn't even talk to women.
只要房间里有一个女人  你就不敢出声
I mean, you couldn't even talk if one was in the room.
很好  现在我可以说
Oh, great, now I can say
"我真不敢相信你要和我分手"
things like I can't believe you're breaking up with me.
"你为什么和我分手"
Why are you breaking up with me,
"是  我还是会帮你搬家的"
Yes, I'll still help you move.
还有人想试试吗
Anyone else want to try?
我有话要说
Uh, yeah, I got something.
拉杰
Raj,
不是所有人  都能做狗的主人
not everybody could be a dog owner.
怎么啦  你的狗狗也和你分手了吗
Oh, what? Did your doggie break up with you too?
我在自动贩卖机买了巧克力豆
Hey, I bought M&Ms at the vending machine
结果出来两包
and two bags came out.
第一包是我买的
I bought the first one,
投币后没出来
it didn't fall.
给
Here.
她出生了  宝宝出生了
She's here, the baby's here!
恭喜了
Congratulations!
伯纳黛特好吗
How's Bernadette?
很累  但是很好
Tired, but great.
母女都平安
They're both great.
给宝宝取了名字吗
Does the baby have a name yet?
我们给她取名叫哈雷
We have named her Halley.
哈雷彗星的名字
Oh, like Halley's comet.
是的
Exactly.
与哈雷彗星相同的还有一点
Also like the comet, Bernadette said
伯纳黛特说她每隔75年才和我上床一次
she's not gonna have sex with me for another 75 years.
这不是真的  他只是开玩笑
That's not a real thing, he's just joking.
我要回去了
I'm gonna get back.
感谢你们的陪伴  我迫不及待想让哈雷见见
Thank you for staying up, I can't wait for Halley to meet
她的叔叔阿姨们
her new aunts and uncles
还有教父
and godfather.
真的吗
Really?
当然
Of course.
听到了吗  斯图尔特
You hear that, Stuart?!
我有狗有教女  你屁都没有
I've got a dog and a godchild, you have nothing!
看这些小宝宝
Oh, look at all the babies!
有些会成为成功人士
Some will be successful,
有些可能会做流浪汉
some may be homeless.
想想就觉得有趣
It's fun to think about.
不知道哪个是哈雷
I wonder which one's Halley.
很难看清楚名字
Kind of hard to see the names.
那个长的像伯纳黛特
Mm, that one kind of looks like Bernadette.
我觉得都长一个样子
They all look the same to me.
伙计们
Guys,
她是我的教女
she's my goddaughter,
我想我看到她时会认出来的
I think I'll know when I see her.
那个
That one.
好累的一天
Well, that was quite a day.
是的
It was.
伯纳黛特生了孩子
Bernadette had her baby,
我去了魔法世界
I made it to Wizarding World,
现在是时候完成你的生日庆典了
and now it is time to complete your birthday celebration.
听我所令
Hankius
宽衣解带
pankius.
我还担心你会太累呢
I was afraid you'd be too tired.
艾米  我刚看到了魔法火车
Amy, I just saw a magic train
还举报了有人插队
and reported somebody for cutting the line.
如果这都不算前戏  那我不知道还能怎么戏了
If that's not foreplay, I don't know what is.